I'm shocked! I cannot believe Twitch is actually finally making bot busting a priority on the platform.
Botting on Twitch has been a problem since the beginning of time.
And they hadn't taken it seriously forever, but a month ago they made a statement where they
claimed, listen guys, condoms finally coming off, we're going in raw against bots, we're finally
gonna do something about it. And I was excited, like that's something to celebrate, but I kind of
thought they were just looking to score some good boy points online, like some brownie points
because Twitch's reputation been kind of in the shitter recently. I thought this was just
something that they were just doing for lip service. I wasn't entirely convinced they were going
to go that hard on it until today. Wow, they have actually done a really good job here, like in this
first wave of getting bots off of Twitch, like bringing back down these artificially boosted numbers
to what they actually are. There's a lot of examples to pull from the data is all very new,
mind you, but I think the best example is from a channel called Mira. I'm sure some of you have
at least heard of this because this is something that people have been trying to put on Twitch's
plate for the longest time about a channel that keeps getting recommended to them that isn't actually
even a livestream. For the last couple of years, it is just a farming channel where Mira is just
farming ads of botted numbers. She doesn't actually even really stream on there. I think she's gone
live like a few times over the last couple of years, but it's live 24-7 just pumping reruns of
streams she did so long ago, like ancient history. So look at this, this channel for I think like
probably three years. I don't know how long it's been going on for, but it's been years has been
sitting at like a steady 2000 viewers no matter the time of day. And all the channel has done for this
pretty much exclusively is run 24-7 reruns of old streams yet somehow manages to maintain 2000
viewers throughout the entire duration of it. Then the day that Twitch bot smiting comes into effect,
it goes from 2000 then down to 1500 and then the bot detection I guess most have kicked into
fucking turbo drive. They went 1-bo style and now she's sitting at 100 to 200. Pretty much
overnight. This to me is like the most clear example of them actually doing something about botting.
I was very surprised to see this. Her channel which is live right now by the way because it's 24-7
reruns. This channel is constantly or was constantly recommended to anybody with a brand new account
like see I'm not logged in or anything. I'm still on like light mode. This stream was recommended
all the time and somehow still had 1000 viewers on just reruns. Clearly most like rational
sentient human beings aren't going to be watching that. Look at the chat. It doesn't move and
this is exactly what it looked like back then too. No movement. There's no chatting because it's not
real. And now the bot detection is here and you can see that it is finally working. Though I think
there are still some bots like some holdovers here because there's no way there's 250 people here
right now. It seems to me like there's definitely still some stubborn bots that Twitch wasn't able to
get there. Stick it on there like a hemorrhoid. The parasite bot infestation has been decimated but
not destroyed because I cannot imagine 276 people being in this stream right now. Not even his
background noise in like a tab they forgot on like an ancient laptop. I don't even see that being
the case. I don't think there's a single soul in this realm right now. This shit is more empty
than a theater showing more beasts. I just don't believe that. But even still it's clear that what
Twitch is doing is actually pretty effective at blasting bots which I didn't expect. Her channel
I think is the best example of it. But there's a lot of other channels like big streamers that went
live over the last day where their view counts have halved or even more than halved in some cases.
So they actually are taking it kind of seriously. Like I said I was a little skeptical that they were
even going to really try and take down bots because inflated viewer numbers is good for the platform.
Like I thought they probably wouldn't actually put a lot of resources to it. But it seems I was very
wrong. Now another thing worth mentioning. This scam of like running reruns with bots is not
exclusive to just her channel. But you have to wonder how much money she made off of that. This
is so curious how much money she made just running old streams 24-7 reruns with botted view counts
up to 2-3,000. That's probably a pretty substantial chunk of change. It's got a lot of people talking
and I think this is a really great thing from Twitch to be honest. XQC made a tweet talking about
it saying Twitch cracked down on bots in 2-3 days and viewbots, slash victims of viewbots have been
exposed. Streamers that are part of group slash orgs are seemingly being botted much more heavily.
Don't want to start a witch hunt but the data is interesting to go see for yourself
and then links Twitch tracker which you can see for yourself. And people are scrubbing through
with a fine tooth comb taking a peek at these big drops in viewer numbers. And right now the findings
are still pretty early because this has only been an effect for like two maybe three days now.
So it's still like very fresh data. This shit's straight out of the oven. But people are noticing that
some of the biggest channels being hit were affiliated with orgs. So like XQC mentions,
like some org affiliated channels were in a lot of cases the recipients of some artificially
boosted numbers as evident by a huge drop in viewer numbers over the last couple days. I don't
know where. Namely OTK seems to be the big one people are seeing a huge drop across the board
for most of the channels that have gone live over the last couple days that are with the group.
Another channel people been paying very close attention to is Asman Golds. He's one of the
biggest streamers in the world and he went live the last couple days since the bot fisting has come
out from Twitch and they noticed that his average viewers for both streams had been about 20,000
less than normal. About 20,000 people were banished to the shadow realm here and Asman Gold even
commented on it believing that his account was probably bought it. He believes with 95% certainty
his channel was bought it and he agrees that removing these bot numbers and this fake phony
baloney viewership from the platform is good for everybody there. And that seems to be the
prevailing sentiment that everyone agrees that getting rid of artificial viewership from Twitch
is a net positive to the entire platform. The only people that will have an issue with these
fake numbers being blasted is going to be the people that are exploiting them. The people that
are using the bot services are the only ones that are going to be outraged about it. Now I also
imagine the cope from a lot of people that are going to get caught red handed with bots is going to be
it wasn't me I must have been the victim of a malicious bot villain a super villain twirling his
evil cartoonish mustache must have been botting me for all this time. I had no idea. And in some cases
like that is a real thing. There are cases where some people will bot a channel just because they
think it's going to get them in trouble. But that doesn't happen like Twitch for the longest time
has not taken this botting problem seriously. So that whole idea of like a bad actor botting a
channel to try and get punishment put upon a streamer they don't like. It's not that common. It
happens sure but it's not that common because everybody knows Twitch hasn't done anything about
botters for so long. So how the fuck could that possibly still be a strategy that someone that
doesn't like you would use. That's like you and your buddy going to the public pool and you eat
pizza together and then your friend tries to tell the lifeguard that you didn't wait 30 minutes before
getting in the pool. It's like okay who gives a fuck. I guess the whole way Twitch is treated
botting for the longest time. Until now I think that's going to be like the crutch a lot of people will
claim like I wasn't botting. I didn't sign off on anyone botting me. This must have been some
stranger in the in the back alleys trying to hurt my reputation by botting me for all this time.
And some people I'm sure will be telling the truth but it's going to be hard to know for sure.
But one thing that I think everyone will know for sure is that this is a really good thing for
Twitch. I am so glad they're actually taking this seriously and actually wiping out such huge
amounts of bots. I'm hoping they are still going to continue doing this because there's still work
to be done. All of these bot services are going to do their best to circumvent this so that way
their clients can continue to pay them money for this service. They're not just going to roll over
and die. They're not going to go belly up and just admit defeat. This is always a tug of war.
They are going to come up with new ways of trying to evade Twitch's detection and I'm hoping
this isn't just like a one time thing where Twitch blew their whole load here on this bot blast.
I'm hoping they will continue to allocate resources to fighting against the upcoming bots that
are going to be no doubt surfacing soon. But either way this is a great step in the right direction
and I hope it continues. Just wanted to yap about it a bit. That's it. See ya.